<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>training on Darya Vanichkina</title>
    <link>/tags/training/</link>
    <description>Recent content in training on Darya Vanichkina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/training/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jumping into digital: Lessons learned while moving live-coding workshops online</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-ardc-presentation-codingonline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-ardc-presentation-codingonline/</guid>
      <description>I presented a talk about &amp;ldquo;Jumping into digital: Lessons learned while moving live-coding workshops online&amp;rdquo; at the ARDC community webinar series in April 2020.
The abstract of my talk was:
At ResBaz 2019, I said (on camera) that it is impossible to run a hands-on, live-coding digital skills training workshop online. In March 2020, I led a team of trainers to do exactly this - move our 2-day, Carpentries-style, hands-on Machine Learning in R and Machine Learning in python workshops fully online - in a week!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping a live coding workshop for digital delivery (part 2)</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-map-digital-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-map-digital-2/</guid>
      <description>With the advent of COVID-19 we’re all having to do the unthinkable, which for an instructor like me means moving hands-on, practical coding workshops online. I&amp;rsquo;ve already written a post with a student-facing map of the process (and some tips for students), but I wanted to focus on a few instructor-related aspects of the map in this post.
My personal teaching setup   I&amp;rsquo;m incredibly lucky to have access to several machines, which I use to work through materials on all of the platforms and also while teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping a live coding workshop for digital delivery</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-map-digital-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-map-digital-1/</guid>
      <description>With the advent of COVID-19 we’re all having to do the unthinkable, which for an instructor like me means moving hands-on, practical coding workshops online. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide a map that helped me formalise how I broke down our workshops into components, and tried to map each of them to an online tool, platform or approach. I&amp;rsquo;ve used Zoom for most of the examples below, since that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve used for teaching, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure that most of this functionality is well supported by other online meeting tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Having a great online learning experience: a guide for students</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-great-online-learning-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-great-online-learning-student/</guid>
      <description>With the advent of COVID-19 we’re all having to do the unthinkable, which for an instructor like me means moving hands-on, practical coding workshops online. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll outline a few key things you can do as a learner to have what is hopefully the best possible experience attending synchronous online training.
1. Follow your instructor&amp;rsquo;s instructions Install all the things - and test them First and foremost, triple-check that you have installed everything your instructor has suggested, and tested - as much as you know how to - that it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training the trainer presentation</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-ands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-ands/</guid>
      <description>  ANDS_TrainingTheTrainer  from Darya Vanichkina </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>