<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Darya Vanichkina</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Darya Vanichkina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R for Data Science Day 1</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-r-for-data-science-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-r-for-data-science-day-1/</guid>
      <description>I am incredibly excited that RStudio has begun an instructor certification program based on the Carpentries, so of course I signed up as soon as my overcommited nature allowed! This also provides me with the excuse and motivation to finally formally work my way through R for Data Science, a book I have read while waiting for GTT tests during my pregnancy and google-landed upon an umpteen number of times while debugging code, but never taken the time to sit down and do the exercises for - and of course the pedagogue in me knows quite well that THAT is how you actually learn and internalise the principles and concepts in any material, especially if it deals with programming and analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Hugo</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-moving-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-moving-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m finally making the leap, and (hopefully) moving this website to blogdown + hugo + gitlab + netlify.
So far, useful resources for wrapping my head around how to do this:
 Alison Presmanes Hill&amp;rsquo;s documentation Very useful gotcha for configuring Netlify Non-blogdown specific very detailed outlined (for future reference, when I want to add new page types)  Things that don&amp;rsquo;t seem to work:
 Math! 😭 (but, hey, emoji do!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training the trainer presentation</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-ands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-ands/</guid>
      <description>Presentation on Carpentry Instructor Training - “Training the trainers” given at ANDS Data Seminar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon AWS workshop at the University of Sydney</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-awsworkshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-awsworkshop/</guid>
      <description>On October 24th I attented a talk by Adrian White about using Amazon AWS for research. Below are my notes, not extensively annotated, in the hope that they&amp;rsquo;ll be useful for someone. If something is not clear, please ask in the comments, and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to answer to the best of my knowledge
161024_AWS workshop  SciTeam ~10 ppl  Overview of AWS services  If you need to make your data available you have availability zones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016-PyConAU 2016 Presentation</title>
      <link>/posts/pycon2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/pycon2016/</guid>
      <description>I presented a talk on Big data biology for pythonistas: getting in on the genomics revolution at PyCon Au 2016.
In the abstract, I promised the following:
  In 2001 Bill Clinton unveiled &amp;ldquo;the most important, most wondrous map ever produced by humankind&amp;rdquo; - the human genome. This monumental endeavour cost \$3 billion, and took hundreds of scientists from all over the world 13 years. Today, a single person can generate such a map in ~2 days for $1000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lorne Genome 2012 poster</title>
      <link>/posts/2014-lorne2012poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014-lorne2012poster/</guid>
      <description>Better late than never: my now-published Lorne Genome 2012 poster:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013 ciRNA papers</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-cirnapapers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013-cirnapapers/</guid>
      <description>A presentation I made for a journal club on the &amp;ldquo;1st&amp;rdquo; 3 ciRNA papers
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-helloworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013-helloworld/</guid>
      <description>This is the 1st post for this new Jekyll-powered blog.
Welcome to my blog!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>