<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Darya Vanichkina</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Darya Vanichkina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Living dangerously: a newbie guide to running multiple version of R on a Mac</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-rswitch-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-rswitch-guide/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;d have to be living under a rock in the R community to not be aware of the fact that R 4.0 has been released, with some major changes, the biggest of which is probably the new default for read.table(): stringsAsFactors = FALSE, as well as the fact that matrix() now converts character columns to factors and factors to integers.
In the past, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been too &amp;ldquo;chicken&amp;rdquo; to try running multiple versions of R on my work laptop, as I&amp;rsquo;ve usually got a few key analysis projects going that need to be delivered on time and within full feature scope - which means I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to fix basic version incompatibility bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jumping into digital: Lessons learned while moving live-coding workshops online</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-ardc-presentation-codingonline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-ardc-presentation-codingonline/</guid>
      <description>I presented a talk about &amp;ldquo;Jumping into digital: Lessons learned while moving live-coding workshops online&amp;rdquo; at the ARDC community webinar series in April 2020.
The abstract of my talk was:
At ResBaz 2019, I said (on camera) that it is impossible to run a hands-on, live-coding digital skills training workshop online. In March 2020, I led a team of trainers to do exactly this - move our 2-day, Carpentries-style, hands-on Machine Learning in R and Machine Learning in python workshops fully online - in a week!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping a live coding workshop for digital delivery (part 2)</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-map-digital-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-map-digital-2/</guid>
      <description>With the advent of COVID-19 we’re all having to do the unthinkable, which for an instructor like me means moving hands-on, practical coding workshops online. I&amp;rsquo;ve already written a post with a student-facing map of the process (and some tips for students), but I wanted to focus on a few instructor-related aspects of the map in this post.
My personal teaching setup   I&amp;rsquo;m incredibly lucky to have access to several machines, which I use to work through materials on all of the platforms and also while teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping a live coding workshop for digital delivery</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-map-digital-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-map-digital-1/</guid>
      <description>With the advent of COVID-19 we’re all having to do the unthinkable, which for an instructor like me means moving hands-on, practical coding workshops online. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide a map that helped me formalise how I broke down our workshops into components, and tried to map each of them to an online tool, platform or approach. I&amp;rsquo;ve used Zoom for most of the examples below, since that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve used for teaching, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure that most of this functionality is well supported by other online meeting tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Having a great online learning experience: a guide for students</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-great-online-learning-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-great-online-learning-student/</guid>
      <description>With the advent of COVID-19 we’re all having to do the unthinkable, which for an instructor like me means moving hands-on, practical coding workshops online. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll outline a few key things you can do as a learner to have what is hopefully the best possible experience attending synchronous online training.
1. Follow your instructor&amp;rsquo;s instructions Install all the things - and test them First and foremost, triple-check that you have installed everything your instructor has suggested, and tested - as much as you know how to - that it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R for Data Science Day 1</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-r-for-data-science-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-r-for-data-science-day-1/</guid>
      <description>I am incredibly excited that RStudio has begun an instructor certification program based on the Carpentries, so of course I signed up as soon as my overcommited nature allowed! This also provides me with the excuse and motivation to finally formally work my way through R for Data Science, a book I have read while waiting for GTT tests during my pregnancy and google-landed upon an umpteen number of times while debugging code, but never taken the time to sit down and do the exercises for - and of course the pedagogue in me knows quite well that THAT is how you actually learn and internalise the principles and concepts in any material, especially if it deals with programming and analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Hugo</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-moving-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-moving-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m finally making the leap, and (hopefully) moving this website to blogdown + hugo + gitlab + netlify.
So far, useful resources for wrapping my head around how to do this:
 Alison Presmanes Hill&amp;rsquo;s documentation Very useful gotcha for configuring Netlify Non-blogdown specific very detailed outlined (for future reference, when I want to add new page types)  Things that don&amp;rsquo;t seem to work:
 Math! 😭 (but, hey, emoji do!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training the trainer presentation</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-ands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-ands/</guid>
      <description>  ANDS_TrainingTheTrainer  from Darya Vanichkina </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon AWS workshop at the University of Sydney</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-awsworkshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-awsworkshop/</guid>
      <description>On October 24th I attented a talk by Adrian White about using Amazon AWS for research. Below are my notes, not extensively annotated, in the hope that they&amp;rsquo;ll be useful for someone. If something is not clear, please ask in the comments, and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to answer to the best of my knowledge
161024_AWS workshop  SciTeam ~10 ppl  Overview of AWS services   If you need to make your data available you have availability zones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2016-PyConAU 2016 Presentation</title>
      <link>/posts/pycon2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/pycon2016/</guid>
      <description>I presented a talk on Big data biology for pythonistas: getting in on the genomics revolution at PyCon Au 2016.
Video  Slides   Big data biology for pythonistas: getting in on the genomics revolution  from Darya Vanichkina  Abstract In 2001 Bill Clinton unveiled &amp;ldquo;the most important, most wondrous map ever produced by humankind&amp;rdquo; - the human genome. This monumental endeavour cost $3 billion, and took hundreds of scientists from all over the world 13 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lorne Genome 2012 poster</title>
      <link>/posts/2014-lorne2012poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014-lorne2012poster/</guid>
      <description>Better late than never: my now-published Lorne Genome 2012 poster:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013 ciRNA papers</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-cirnapapers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013-cirnapapers/</guid>
      <description>A presentation I made for a journal club on the &amp;ldquo;1st&amp;rdquo; 3 ciRNA papers
  Comparing the early ciRNA papers   from Darya Vanichkina  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-helloworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013-helloworld/</guid>
      <description>This is the 1st post for this new Jekyll-powered blog.
Welcome to my blog!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Darya, a Data Scientist &amp;amp; Professional Educator. I work at the University of Sydney&amp;rsquo;s Informatics Hub as a data science consultant, supporting researchers from across the university by solving their big (and not-so-big) data problems. I also coordinate SIH&amp;rsquo;s data science training program, where I mentor staff in best teaching practices, develop and deliver advanced analytics training for researchers.
I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about using data to understand the world, and love solving real problems using data science, machine learning, statistics and high-performance/cloud computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Electronic address d.[lastname] at gmail [dot] com
Physical address Sydney Informatics Hub 32 Queen Street Ground Floor Chippendale NSW 2008  Links to other websites  GitHub Academia.edu Figshare ORCID  ResearchGate Slideshare  Google Scholar  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum vitae</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>Please download my full curriculum vitae or an infographic version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training</title>
      <link>/training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/training/</guid>
      <description>I am a Fellow of the UK Higher Education Academy (FHEA) and am passionate about using evidence-based teaching practices for supporting adult leaners in developing digital skills.
As part of my role at the Sydney Informatics Hub, I develop and deliver training for researchers at the University of Sydney. Please see here for upcoming courses. Recently, I:
 Developed and delivered a 2 day Machine learning using R course (Sydney Uni access only).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>